Guide to the Arthur Kopit Papers MSS.141
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV: Personal Materials
  - Personal Materials Box 5, 1953-1970; 31142050719007 (Box 113)
    Materials mostly from Kopit's college years at Harvard: handwritten and type script drafts of "One Morning in June", student papers and examination books, notebooks, high school newspapers, clippings from the NY Times relating to Kopit works, tickets playbills and ephemera relating to student productions, some magazines of the period; one folder of assorted correspondence to and from Kopit along with many envelopes enclosing reviews and notices of various productions; a mostly empty photo album with photos dating as late as 1970, playbills, reviews, photographs of various productions of "Oh Dad...", numerous promotional photos of Kopit,
    Eugene O'Neill, Desire Under the Elms (Signet: New York, 1958)
    "Les Petits Chanteuse de la Renaissance" 45 phonograph.
  - Personal Materials Box 6 Oversize, 31142050719015 (Box 114)
    Gigantic amount of newspaper, mostly copies of the Harvard crimson with other assorted clippings, check register from 1964-1965, a copy of the hardcover periodical "Eros", a red handmade flag with a white letter "H", a framed news clipping of 1963 and a framed Drama Desk Award from 1962; roll of three photocopies of 1962 Outer Circle Award,
    Two LP phonographs, labeled "Harvard Radio Network"
    Note: Realia to possibly deaccession include a completely blank appointment book, a wire "in" basket, a brass box and a box containing a variety of bibelots including tie pins, dice, and a hash pipe moved to box 101a
  - Personal Materials Box 7, ca. 1955-1987; 31142050719023 (Box 115)
    More juvenilia and material from Kopit's college days including early handwritten and typescript drafts of "Sing to Me Through Open Windows", "Oh Dad, Poor Dad...", and "The Death of Houdini"; correspondence to Kopit and to and from his parents George and Maxine Kopit, among them a letter from Edith Adams Kovacs (the comedienne Edie Adams), humorous pencil sketches possibly by Jerome Robbins, a large quantity of photographs, particularly from Kopit's sojourn in Italy (numerous copies of various sizes of most of them); various travel documents; some correspondence and clippings from 1967 relating to productions; a large amount of congratulatory telegrams upon the 1962 premiere of "Oh Dad, Poor Dad..." including messages from Tennessee Williams, Tallulah Bankhead, Edie Adams, Stephen Sondheim, Hugh Beaumont, Edward Albee, and others. After the files of telegrams, a new set of records begins composed mostly of correspondence. One small group of letters dated ca. 1974 are between Peter Hall, Trevor Nunn and Audrey Wood concerning the production of "Discovery of America". Thence follows a large group of correspondence ranging from 1981, to 1988 including mailings from the Writer's Guild and the Dramatists Guild, a fifteen page letter from Kopit to Andrew Lloyd Weber discussing his views on Phantom of the Opera, various personal and casual letters, some correspondence between Kopit and Edward Albee, birthday cards, etc. Finally there is a small group of older correspondence (ca. 1955-1958) at the back of the box mainly of letters between Kopit and his parents during his time at Harvard and a group of "childhood photos-older photos"
    "Music for 'Open Windows'" 1 cassette of casual music composed for regional production, in envelope with letter.
  - Personal Materials Box 8, 1961-ca. 1990; 31142050719031 (Box 116)
    Correspondence, ca. 1961-1968, between Kopit and various friends, Leslie Garis and Kopit's parents, much written during the production of "Indians" in London. Box also contains monthly appointment calendars from the years 1978, 1980-1984, 1986, and 1988-1989; desk diaries from 1979, 1980 and 1982, and a folder of numerous playbills.
  - Personal Materials Box 9, 31142050719049 (Box 117)
    Oversized materials from previous box including wall calendars and large sections of newspapers. Realia separated from previous boxes includes a silver box of foreign currency and a red garter, completely blank appointment book, a wire "in" basket, a brass box and a box containing a variety of bibelots including tie pins, dice, and a hash pipe, Life magazines, deck of playing cards, rock. matchbox car, painting by Kat Kopit, box of sleeve patches (such as are found on overalls)
  - Personal Materials Box 10, 31142050719056 (Box 118)
    Large amount of unsorted color photographs (some fairly recent) and slides; older black and white photographs; large box of unsorted 35mm color slides (completely unlabeled but possibly research on "Indians"); quantity of negatives 35mm and larger, 1 undeveloped role of color film; 3 unidentified reel to reel audio tapes; framed photographs and certificate, chromatic harmonica, medallion from Legion of Honor, oversized photocopies of Drama Desk Award and newspaper articles;Audio Recordings
    Reel to reel tapes
    "Lewis and Clark Interviews"
    "Rose Lischner Shenandoah"
    "Raul, Len, Ahab(?) and interview"
  - Personal Materials Box 11, ca.1950-1963; 31142050719064 (Box 119)
    Degrees, certificates and some photos, all framed, high school yearbooks, childhood catcher's mitt.
  - Personal Materials Box 12, ca.1950-1963; 31142050719072 (Box 120)
    Personal materials removed from "Miscellaneous" boxes". Includes letters from letter files marked "to be answered" ca. 1978-1979; materials from a box marked "very important Harvard scripts" and including handwritten script, possibly from "The Questioning of Nick", handwritten and typescript materials on "The Runway of Life...", unidentified script drafts possibly from "Sing to Me Through Open Windows", correspondence and other materials dating throughout the 1960s; the next group of material is random family documents, particularly of Kopit's children; maps, train schedules and Zagat's restaurant guide.
    Zagat Survey, 1998 New York City Restaurants (Zagat Survey: New York, 1998.
    Note: One folder of oversized sheets of handwritten script of unidentified play ("Sing to Me..."?) moved to Flat Box 15. Realia moved to box 117, includes deck of playing cards, rock. matchbox car, painting by Kat Kopit, box of sleeve patches (such as are found on overalls)
- Series V: Miscellaneous
  These materials can best be described by reading the individual box descriptions. They were among materials received from Kopit marked as "Miscellaneous". Most of the materials marked this way, however, were merged into the more appropriate categories of projects, personal or business records. Upon further processing, the following two boxes may be dissolved as well.
  - Miscellaneous Box 1, 31142050719080 (Box 121)
    Photographs, stray pamphlets, programs, religious materials, date book with entries from 1969 and 1982, articles, notebook and file of materials on musical concept "Don Juan", mess of materials found jumbled together and seemingly related to various projects, much of the material seems to be stuff collected in pants pockets from business meetings (kleenex, pens, matchbooks, etc.).
    Otto von Pivka, Armies of the Middle East (Mayflower Books: New York, 1979)
    Note: One folder of legal sized materials moved to Flat Box 15 including film rights contract for "Indians". Box includes fez.
  - Miscellaneous Box 2, 31142050719098 (Box 122)
    Album of news clippings and other odd materials.
    Robert C. Aldridge, The Counterforce Syndrome (Institute for Policy Studies: Washington, D.C., 1978)
    Note: One folder of oversized material, possible research material on "End of the World", files marked "Ropongo" moved to Flat Box 15
- Series VI: Scripts and Works by Other Authors
  These materials were found in two or three discrete groups among Kopit's papers. Many are pieces by authors Kopit had worked with or was expecting to work with. Some appear to be unsolicited and some may be by current or former students of Kopit. While most of the works are plays or books for musicals, there are a handful of manuscripts of novels and nonfiction works as well.
  - Scripts Box 1, 31142050719106 (Box 123)
    "Comfortable Shoes" by Clint Holmes, 1998
    "Wellwishers" by Katherine Lynn Louis, 1995
    "Sabina" by Willy Holtzman, 1993
    "The Death of Baldur: A Study of Idealization" by Nancy L. Neiman-Hoffman, 1986
    C.V. of Eric-Emmanuel Schmitt, 1997
    Various pieces by Lauren Rosenberg, ca. 1997
    untitled work by William Beruh, 1995
    "The Crash Victims" by Ole Bornedal, 1996
    "The Hour" by John Sisk, 1996
    "The Produce King of Hub City" by Richard Molson, 1996
    "A Fair Country" by John Robin Baitz, 1995
    "The Strange Case of Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde" by David Edgar, 1991
    "Half Past Love" by Marilyn A. Hatch, with criticisms and annotations by Kopit
    "Script 82/83", annual publication of NYU student work
    "Liberal and Other Arts" by Howard Junker, 1984
    Work by or about "Helen Whitten". possibly titled "The Journey", ca. 1986
    "The Smile of Smiles" by Sidney Hart, undated
    "Leo and Ellie" by Gil Perlroth, 1993
    "Dancing With You" by Gil Perlroth, 1993
    "A Chambers Play" by jack Gelber, undated
    "Cancer in Laboratory Animals" by Louise Williams, 1987
    "These are the Jokes" by Max Wilk, 1988
    "Mandy" by Joan Sorkin and Gene P. Bissell, 1988
    "Goodman Brown" by Stephen Sheppard,, undated
    "This Winter's Hobby" by Jack Finney, undated
  - Scripts Box 2, 31142050719114 (Box 124)
    Information on the Collaborative Theater Project, 1988
    "Czar of the Movies" by Tony Macaulay and Larry Shue, 1984, treatment, book and correspondence
    "The White Crow: Eichmann in Jerusalem" by Donald Freed, 1985
    "Jekyll and Hyde" by Frank Wildhorn and Steven Cuden, 1986
    "Place Your Bets" by Gianni Bozzacchi et al., undated
    "Common Men" by Jeffrey Gallagher, 1985
    "Dusky sally" by Granville Burgess, 1982
    "The End of the Trail" by Francine Sterey, undated
    "Inner Logic" by Keith Reddin, 1978
    "Grant" by Edward Grinnan, undated
    "One Man's Ceiling is Another Man's Floor" by Keith Reddin, undated
    "Cabaret Piece" by Keith Reddin, undated
    "Funnies?" by Keith Reddin, undated
    "Exhibition(ists)" by Keith Reddin, undated, also other fragments posssibly by Reddin
    "A New World's Record" by John Gehm, undated
    Various course materials or records
    "Keepsakes" by Nancy Beardsley, undated
    "Rush Act" by Harry Kondoleon, undated
    "Back to Normal" by Harry Kondoleon, 1978
    Unknown fragment.
    "Lorenzo in the New World" by Gerald Walker, undated
    Xerox of "The Dream Lover" by Lawrence Sanders, 1987
    "Helltown" by Jon Freeman, 1992
    "La Verite sur Maman" by Giles Laurent, 1992
    "The Cork in Heaven" by Simeon Hellerman, 1993
    "Cross my Heart and Hope to Live" by Claire Sylvia and Robert Bosnak, 1992
    "The Lady Who Swings the Band" by Eric Overmyer, 1990
- Series VIII: Oversize Materials, 0 Linear Feet
  The following boxes contain oversized materials separated from throughout the collection. The boxes include newspapers and magazines, legal documents, note pads, sketchbooks sketch pads and pages from such books, posters, photographs and the like. Materials are in folders marked with their box and series of origin and the folders are described below. Notes describing oversized material located here are also contained within each originating box description.
  - Box 1 Projects: two sketchbooks from "Animal Hospital", cuid22052 (Box Flat Box 1)
    Box 8 Projects: sketch pads and exhibition catalog used for "Deception".
  - Box 9 Projects: legal sized notes and script copies of "Discovery of America"., cuid22053 (Box Flat Box 2)
    Box 12 Projects: sketch pads, pages and notes for "Dreamhouse".
    Box 13 Projects: magazine for "End of the World".
  - Box 15 Projects: two folders of sketch pages and notes for "End of the World"., cuid22054 (Box Flat Box 3)
    Box 16 Projects: three folders of maps, magazines and research for "End of the World"
  - Box 19 Projects: notebook from "Hands of a Stranger"., cuid22055 (Box Flat Box 4)
    Box 20 Projects: sketchbook from "High Society"
    Box 26 Projects: Research and notes form "In a Child's Name" ("Legacy of a Mother's Murder") work with Peter Maas.
  - Box 27 Projects: "MK-Ultra" sketch pages and notes., cuid22056 (Box Flat Box 5)
    Box 28 Projects: two folders of contracts and legal pads from "Nine".
    Box 31 Projects:four folders of sketch pages, research materials, magazine from "Phantom".
  - Box 33 Projects: sketch pages from "Roy Steinberg Project", cuid22057 (Box Flat Box 6)
    Box 34 Projects: roll of posters from Steppenwolf production, handbills, three legal folders of galleys of "Road to Nirvana".
  - Box 38 Projects: One large legal-sized photocopy of complete manuscript by Valdamar Valerian and small amount of sketches and notes from "Roswell", cuid22058 (Box Flat Box 7)
    Box 39 Projects: "Scientific Process" sketch pages.
    Box 43 Projects: three folders including two oversized rolls of maps, one legal folder of same with handwritten notes and pages, one folder of contracts and correspondence.
  - Box 43 Projects: Five sketchbooks from "The Shroud", cuid22059 (Box Flat Box 8)
    Box 49 Projects: tow folders of sketchbook pages and notes from "Sweet Smell of Success".
  - Box 51 Projects: folder of sketchbook pages from "Till Us Do Part", cuid22060 (Box Flat Box 9)
    Box 52 Projects: Folder of sketchbook pages and legal pad, "Treasure Island".
    Box 53 Projects: Legal pads, "Treasure Island"
    Box 54 Projects: legal pads and sketchpad, "Treasure Island"
    Box 55 Projects: sketch page, maps from "Treasure Island"
    Box 59 Projects: Galley proofs, manuscript fragments and notes from "Wings".
  - Box 59 Projects: 3 folders on "Wings"., cuid22061 (Box Flat Box 10)
    Box 60 Projects: "Wings" sketchbook pages.
    Box 62 Projects: sketchbook pages from "Norman in Wonderland".
    Large sketchbook pages and other materials from "Dr. Zhivago".
  - Box 65 Projects: folder of oversized drawing from "Lewis and Clark", cuid22062 (Box Flat Box 11)
    Box 70 Projects: one folder of "Notes on 'Men Are From Mars...'; roll of large pencil sketches, apparently studies for "Lewis and Clark"; Oversized sketchbook pages of "Blindsight"; Photocopies of handwritten drafts of "Discovery of America"; photocopied book "The Two Hundred Days of 8 1/2" by Deena Boyer...."; oversized notebook, apparently of "Mhil'Daiim".
  - Box 72 Projects: folder of handwritten and typescript drafts, character sketches, outlines, and exploration of names, all for unknown work dated 1975., cuid22063 (Box Flat Box 12)
    Box 73 Projects: folder of legal size material on "Starstruck"
    Box 74 Projects: folder of draft of "Snatch" legal-sized pages
    Box 75 Projects: two folders of "Eureka" Materials, large sketchbook pages for "Dreamhouse"
    Box 76 Projects: one oversized folder of material on "Chamber Music", one folder of "Oh Dad, Poor Dad..." (original film contract); one of "Nine", unidentified handwritten script from 1976.
  - Box 78 Miscellaneous: two folders of oversized material including correspondence and contracts with ICM and a French translation of "The Day the Whores..." moved to Flat Box 13., cuid22064 (Box Flat Box 13)
    Box 79 Projects: folder of oversized material, magazine, poster and photo from different years.
    Box 83 Projects: 3 very large sketchbooks from "End of the World".
  - Box 97 Business: heavily annotated wall calendar from 1997, plaques., cuid22065 (Box Flat Box 14)
    Box 98 Business: folder of "Phantom" contracts
    Box 99 Business: folder of material on home appraisal and mortgage, one folder of trust agreements, two award plaques.
    Box 106 Business: legal folder of material, all royalty statements.
  - Box 107 Business: folder of Tony Award material, cuid22066 (Box Flat Box 15)
    Box 120 Personal: folder of oversized sheets of handwritten script of unidentified play ("Sing to Me..."?)
    Box 121 Miscellaneous: folder of legal sized materials including film rights contract for "Indians".
    Box 122 Miscellaneous: folder of oversized material, possible research material on "End of the World", files marked "Ropongo".
  - Original pastels (rolled), autographed theater posters, word lists, 1984-1998; cuid22070 (Box 134)